Guide to the The Penumbra Foundation Collection of Digitized Photography Manuals CAP.1
New York University Archives
The Penumbra Foundation Collection of Digitized Photography Manuals
1847-1994
1847-1930
New York University Archives
Penumbra Foundation
Taubman, Eric
CAP.1
249 Volumes
The Penumbra Foundation is a photographic arts organization developed to maintain relevant historical and analog photography in the digital age through education, supporting artists' work in historical processes, lecture series, research, residency programs, workshops, and studio and library programs in collaboration with a like-minded community. This collection consists of digitized photographic processing and equipment manuals, as well as volumes documenting the history of photography, generally dating from the mid-19th century to the early-20th century. These materials were collected by members of the Penumbra Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the Penumbra Foundation, 2014.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Historical Note
The Penumbra Foundation was founded in 1998 in New York City. It is a photographic arts organization developed to maintain relevant historical and analog photography in the digital age through education, supporting artists' work in historical processes, lecture series, research, residency programs, workshops, and studio and library programs in collaboration with a like-minded community.
Eric Taubman, co-founder of the Penumbra Foundation, is a fine art photographer and businessman who developed and operated photo labs in New York City and around the world for 30 years. At the time that digital photography was supplanting traditional analog services Eric turned his attention to the Center for Alternative Photography (CAP), a workshop based organization, which later would turn into the Penumbra Foundation, a non-profit 501c3 dedicated to supporting a broad range of historical and analog practices. His passion is the history of photography in all of its forms, processes, art, historical equipment and primary source material. His collection of photographic manuals is unique and comprised of early and rare volumes. Some of these items were owned by well-known photographers of the day.
The Penumbra Collection is complimented by a comprehensive and rare collection of lens manuals and lens catalogs. Geoffrey H. Berliner is the Executive Director of the Penumbra Foundation, a practicing photographer, a well-known portraitist, and a historian of photography. He has an extensive collection of historical lenses, said to be the largest collection in the world and an equally comprehensive collection of lens manuals. This ephemera is often discarded so the lens catalog collection may well represent the last copy left.
Custodial History
These books are from the private collection of members of the Penumbra Foundation who lent the materials to New York University's Digital Library Technology Services for digitization.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of digitized photographic processing and equipment manuals, as well as volumes documenting the history of photography, generally dating from the mid-19th century to the early-20th century. These materials were collected by members of the Penumbra Foundation.
A wide range of photographic topics are covered by the material in this collection. Some topics documented by this collection include the history of photography, the chemistry of photography, and information on creating different types of photographs such as Aristotypes and Ferrotypes. In addition to this material, the collection includes several lense catalogs from the late 19th to early 20th century.
Existence and Location of Originals
Original volumes held by members of the Penumbra Foundation.
Cameras; Photography; Photography Processing
- Digitized Publications
  - Photographic Printing Methods, 1887; cap1_ref1; Burbank, W. H. (William Henry); Scoville Press; 1 bound volume; 9 1/4 inches by 6 1/4 inches, 256 pages (Object 1)
    New York (N.Y.).; Photography
  - Modern Dry Plates or Emulsion Photography, 1881; cap1_ref2; E. & H.T. Anthony (Firm); Josef Maria Eder; 1 bound volume; 8 3/8 inches x 6 1/8 inches, 194 pages (Object 2)
    New York (N.Y.).; Photography; Photographic emulsions
  - The Ferrotype and How to Make It, 1898; cap1_ref13; Edward Estabrook; E. & H.T. Anthony (Firm); 1 bound volume; 7 7/8 inches x 5 3/8 inches, 212 pages (Object 3)
  - A Manual of Photographic Chemistry, 1857; cap1_ref15; John Churchill & Sons; Hardwich, T. Frederick; 1 bound volume; 7 inches x 4 3/4 inches, 416 pages (Object 4)
    London (England).; Photography
  - A History of Photography, 1887; cap1_ref16; Scoville Press; Harrison, W. Jerome (William Jerome), 1845-1909; 1 bound volume; 9 1/4 inches x 6 inches, 177 pages (Object 5)
    Photography; New York (N.Y.).
  - Photography: A Treatise on the Chemical, 1851; cap1_ref20; Hunt, Robert, 1807-1887; John Joseph Griffin and Company; 1 bound volume; 7 3/4 inches x 5 1/4 inches, 276 pages (Object 6)
    Photography; London (England).
  - Changes Produced by Solar Radiation, Unknown; cap1_ref21; 1 bound volume (Object 7)
  - The Chemistry of Photography, 1891; cap1_ref22; Macmillan Company; Meldola, Raphael, 1849-1915; 1 bound volume; 5 3/8 inches x 7 3/8 inches, 408 pages (Object 8)
  - A History and Handbook of Photography, 1877; cap1_ref23; Scoville Press; Thomson, J. (John), 1837-1921; Tissandier, Gaston, 1843-1899; 1 bound volume; 7 3/4 inches x 6 inches, 388 pages (Object 9)
  - The Silver Sunbeam, 1879; cap1_ref24; E. & H.T. Anthony (Firm); Towler, John, 1811-1889; 1 bound volume; 5 1/4 inches x 7 7/8 inches, 680 pages (Object 10)
  - Handbook of the Practice and Art of Photography, 1871; cap1_ref25; Moelling, Edward; Benerman & Wilson; Vogel, Hermann Wilhelm, 1834-1898; 1 bound volume; 8 3/4 inches x 6 1/4 inches, 373 pages (Object 11)
    Related Materials
    The Chemistry of Light and Photography by Dr. Hermann Vogel
    Photography; Philadelphia (Pa.)
  - The Chemistry of Light and Photography, 1875; cap1_ref26; Vogel, Hermann Wilhelm, 1834-1898; D. Appleton and Company; 1 bound volume; Dimensions: 5 5/16 inches x 7 11/16 inches, 364 pages (Object 12)
    Handbook of the Practice and Art of Photography by Dr. Hermann Vogel
  - The Evolution of Photography, 1890; cap1_ref27; Piper and Carter; Werge, John, fl., 1854-1890; 1 bound volume; 5 3/8 inches x 7 3/8 inches, 338 pages (Object 13)
  - American Carbon Manual, 1868; cap1_ref28; Scovill and Adams Company; Wilson, Edward L. (Edward Livingston), 1838-1903; 1 bound volume; 5 1/4 inches x 7 1/2 inches, 149 pages (Object 14)
  - Aristotypes and How to Make Them, 1893; cap1_ref29; Woodbury, Walter B. (Walter Bentley), 1834-1885; Scovill and Adams Company; 1 bound volume; Dimensions: 6 inches x 9 1/4 inches, 222 pages (Object 15)
    Aristotype; New York (N.Y.).; Photography
  - The Ferrotyper's Guide, 1896; cap1_ref30; Scovill and Adams Company; 1 bound volume; 4 1/2 inches x 6 1/2 inches, 68 pages (Object 16)
    Photography; Tintype; New York (N.Y.).
  - Handbook of Heliography: The Art of Writing or Drawing by the Effects of Sun-Light, 1860; cap1_ref31; Tyas, Robert, 1811-1879; 1 bound volume; 3 1/2 inches x 5 1/2 inches, 116 pages (Object 17)
    Photography; Sunprinting (Photography); London (England).
  - Wonders of Light and Shadow, 1850; cap1_ref33; Society for Promoting Christian Knowledge (Great Britain); 1 bound volume; 4 1/4 inches x 5 5/8 inches, 120 pages (Object 18)
  - A Popular Treatise on Photography, 1867; cap1_ref32; Monckhoven, D. van (Désiré), 1834-1882; Virtue Brothers and Company; 1 bound volume; 4 1/4 inches x 6 7/8 inches, 203 pages (Object 19)
    A Popular Treatise on Photography by Monckhoven (1863) Ref. 35
  - Practical Photography on Glass and Paper, 1859; cap1_ref34; Bland and Company; Long, Charles A.; 1 bound volume; Dimensions: 4 9/16 inches x 7 inches, (Object 20)
    London (England).
  - A Popular Treatise on Photography, 1863; cap1_ref35; Virtue Brothers and Company; Monckhoven, D. van (Désiré), 1834-1882; 1 bound volume; 4 1/4 inches x 7 inches, 168 pages (Object 21)
    A Popular Treatise on Photography by Monckhoven (1867) Ref. 32
  - Plain Directions for Obtaining Photographic Pictures, 1847; cap1_ref36; Croucher, J. H. (John H.); T. & R. Willats; 1 bound volume; 7 1/2 inches x 4 3/4 inches, 57 pages (Object 22)
  - On the Choice and Use of Photographic Lenses, 1886; cap1_ref37; Dallmeyer, J.H. (John Henry), 1830-1883; Parkins & Gotto; 1 bound volume; 8 3/8 inches x 5 3/8 inches, 44 pages (Object 23)
  - S.O.M. Berthiot, 1923; cap1_ref38; Société anonyme; 1 bound volume; 6 1/8 inches x 9 7/16 inches, 49 pages (Object 24)
    Paris (France)
  - Bausch and Lomb Anastigmatics, Unknown; cap1_ref39; 1 bound volume; 4 1/2 inches x 7 inches, 40 pages (Object 25)
    Rochester (N.Y.); Photography; Photographic lenses
  - Optical Works By C.P. Goerz, 1893; cap1_ref40; Goerz, C. P.; 1 bound volume; Dimensions: 6 5/8 inches x 9 9/16 inches, 28 Pages (Object 26)
    Chicago (Ill.); Photographic lenses
  - Aldis Lenses, Unknown; cap1_ref41; Aldis Brothers; 1 bound volume; Dimensions: 4 13/16 inces x 7 1/2 inches, 20 pages (Object 27)
    Photographic lenses; Photography; Birmingham (England)
  - Rodenstock Photo-Optik, 1927; cap1_ref42; Optische Werke G. Rodenstock; 1 bound volume; 10 7/8 inches x 8 inches, 44 pages (Object 28)
    Photography; Munich (Germany); Photographic lenses
  - Die Photographischen Objektive, Unknown; cap1_ref43; Optische Werke G. Rodenstock; 1 bound volume; 10 7/8 inches x 7 inches, 69 pages (Object 29)
  - Photographic Reproduction Processes, 1891; cap1_ref44; Duchochois, P. C. (Peter C.); Scovill and Adams Company; 1 bound volume; 6 inches x 9 1/4 inches, 187 pages (Object 30)
  - Ilex Photographic Lenses and Shutters, Unknown; cap1_ref116; Arrow Printing Co., Inc.; 1 bound volume; 20 pages (Object 31)
    Rochester (N.Y.); Photography
  - Portrait Veritar Lens, Unknown; cap1_ref119; Wollensak Opitcal Co.; 1 bound volume (Object 32)
    Photography; Rochester (N.Y.)
  - Willemstad Lenses & Shutters, 1914; cap1_ref120; Wollensak Opitcal Co.; 1 bound volume (Object 33)
  - Etablissements J.H. Dallmeyer Limited, Unknown; cap1_ref121; 1 bound volume (Object 34)
    Photography
  - What Type of Lens is Best for my Purpose?, cap1_ref122; Wollensak Opitcal Co.; 1 bound volume (Object 35)
  - Goerz Lenses, 1893; cap1_ref123; 1 bound volume (Object 36)
    Chicago (Ill.)
  - Photographic Lenses Catalog H, cap1_ref124 (Object 37)
  - Objectifs et Appareils Photographiques, cap1_ref125 (Object 38)
  - Objectifs Photographiques, cap1_ref126 (Object 39)
  - Ross Lenses Cameras, etc., cap1_ref128 (Object 40)
  - Photo Lenses, cap1_ref127 (Object 41)
  - Abridged Catalogue for 1906, Cancelling all Previous Lists, cap1_ref129 (Object 42)
  - The Ross Catalogue of Lenses, Cameras etc., cap1_ref130 (Object 43)
  - Photographic Lenses, cap1_ref131 (Object 44)
  - Photographic Lenses and Korons Cameras, cap1_ref132 (Object 45)
  - Why You Should Insist on Dallmeyer Lenses, cap1_ref133 (Object 46)
  - Schneider Lenses, cap1_ref134; 2 bound volume; 24 pages (Object 47)
    Germany.; Photography
  - Ilex Lenses and Shutters, cap1_ref135 (Object 48)
  - Goerz Lenses, cap1_ref136 (Object 49)
  - The Early History of the House of Dallmeyere, cap1_ref137 (Object 50)
  - Catalogue of Photograhic Apparatus and Supplies No. 59, cap1_ref138 (Object 51)
  - Semi-Achromatic Lenses, cap1_ref139 (Object 52)
  - Smith Soft-Focus Lenses, cap1_ref140 (Object 53)
  - "Smith" Soft focus Lenses Semi-Achromat Visual Quality Synthetics Six Series, cap1_ref141 (Object 54)
  - The Artistic, cap1_ref142 (Object 55)
  - Smith Soft-Focus Lenses, cap1_ref143 (Object 56)
  - Photographic Amusements, Illustrated, cap1_ref144 (Object 57)
  - The Photographic Studio A Guide to its construction, design and deletion of a locality, cap1_ref145 (Object 58)
  - Photographic Optics, cap1_ref146 (Object 59)
  - Price List, cap1_ref147 (Object 60)
  - What can be done with the Goerz Lens, cap1_ref148 (Object 61)
  - The Graphlex-Steinjeil Combination, cap1_ref149 (Object 62)
  - Sigmar Lenses for Portrait Photography, cap1_ref150 (Object 63)
  - Semi Centennial Catalog Photographic Lenses Shutters and Apparatus, cap1_ref151 (Object 64)
  - Kalostat The Spectral Diffusion Lens, cap1_ref152 (Object 65)
  - Kalostat The Spectral Diffusion Lens, cap1_ref153 (Object 66)
  - Kalostat The Spectral Diffusion Lens, cap1_ref154 (Object 67)
  - The Kalostat The Lens for the Man who cares, cap1_ref155 (Object 68)
  - New Principles in the Design of Anastigmatic Lenses, cap1_ref156 (Object 69)
  - The Eagle Eye of Your Camera Zeiss Objectives, cap1_ref157 (Object 70)
  - Photographic Lenses and how they are made, cap1_ref158 (Object 71)
  - A Catalogue of Taylor-Hobson Cooke Lenses, cap1_ref159 (Object 72)
  - A Catalog of Cooke Anastigmats For Fine Photography with "Helps to Photographers", cap1_ref160 (Object 73)
  - A Catalog of Cooke Anastigmats For Fine Photography with "Helps to Photographers", cap1_ref161 (Object 74)
  - A Catalog of Cooke Anastigmats For Fine Photography with "Helps to Photographers", cap1_ref162 (Object 75)
  - Catalog & Price List of Photographic Lenses, cap1_ref163 (Object 76)
  - A Catalogue of Photographic Lenses, cap1_ref164 (Object 77)
  - Catalogue General, cap1_ref165 (Object 78)
  - Prix-Courant Des Appareils Photographiques De Tous Genres, cap1_ref166 (Object 79)
  - Goerz Kameras, Objektive und Photo Artikel, undated; cap1_ref231; Goerz, C. P. (Object 80)
  - Cooke Lenses, 1902; cap1_ref232; Taylor, Taylor and Hobson, ltd. (Object 81)
  - The Radioscope A Lens Objective, circa 1904; cap1_ref233; Ewing, Wm. C.; 1 bound volume (Object 82)
  - Photographic Lenses and Shutters, Jan 14, 1930; cap1_ref234; Wollensak Opitcal Co.; 1 bound volume (Object 83)
  - The Kalostat A Lens of Distinction, 1926; cap1_ref235; Hanovia Lens Laboratories; 1 bound volume (Object 84)
  - Beck Lenses, undated; cap1_ref236; R & J Beck, Ltd.; 1 bound volume (Object 85)
  - Rapid Universal and Wide Angle Photographic Objectives and Diaphram Shutter, circa 1900; cap1_ref237; Bausch & Lomb Optical Company; 1 bound volume (Object 86)
  - The Anastigmat Lens as an Aid to Artistic Photography, 1906; cap1_ref238; Bausch & Lomb Optical Company; 1 bound volume (Object 87)
  - The Ambrotype Manual: A Practical Treatise on the Art of Taking Positive Photographs on Glass, Commnly Known as Ambrotypes, 1856; cap1_ref239; Daniel Burgess & Co; N.G. Burgess; 1 bound volume (Object 88)
  - A Dictionary of Photography, 1867; cap1_ref240; Dawson, George G.; Sutton, Thomas, 1818-1875; 1 bound volume (Object 89)
  - Delamotte's Practice of Photography A Manual for Students and Amatuers, 1856; cap1_ref241; Low, Son & Co; Delamotte, Philip H. (Philip Henry), 1821-1889; 1 bound volume (Object 90)
  - Photography in the Studio and Field, 1886; cap1_ref242; Estabrooke, Edward M.; E. & H.T. Anthony (Firm) (Object 91)
  - Photography on Collodion, 1858; cap1_ref243; Longley Brothers, Printers; Waldack, Charles; Neff, Peter Jr. (Object 92)
  - A Manual of Photographic Manipulation, 1887; cap1_ref224 (Object 93)
  - The International Scientific Series: The Nature of Light, 1888; cap1_ref246; Lommel, Eugene, 1837-1899; D. Appleton and Company; 1 bound volume (Object 94)
  - The Philadelphia Photographer, 1868; cap1_ref247; Wilson, Edward L. (Edward Livingston), 1838-1903; Benerman & Wilson; 1 bound volume (Object 95)
  - Photographic Mosaics: An Annual Record of Photographic Process, 1878; cap1_ref248; Wilson, Edward L. (Edward Livingston), 1838-1903; 1 bound volume (Object 96)
  - Treatsie on Photography, 1878; cap1_ref249; de Wiveleslie Abney, William (Sir); Longmans, Green, and Co; 1 bound volume (Object 97)
  - A Manual of Photographic Chemistry, undated; cap1_ref250; 1 bound volume (Object 98)
  - The Stereoscope and Stereoscope Photographs, 1898; cap1_ref251; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894; Wilson, Edward L. (Edward Livingston), 1838-1903; 1 bound volume (Object 99)
  - Micro-Photography, 1883; cap1_ref252; Lewis (H. K.) and Company, ltd., publishers, London.; Malley, A. Cowley; 1 bound volume (Object 100)
  - An Introduction to the Practice of Wet Collodion Photography, 1902; cap1_ref253; Gamble, Charles W., 1867-; Hazell, Watson and Viney, LD; 1 bound volume (Object 101)
  - Collodion Emulsion, 1905; cap1_ref254; A. W. Penrose & Co.; Klein, Henry Oscar; 1 bound volume (Object 102)
  - Organic Photographic Developers, 1920; cap1_ref255; 1 bound volume (Object 103)
  - Philadelphia Photographer, 1880; cap1_ref256; 1 bound volume (Object 104)
  - The Fine Art of Photography, 1919; cap1_ref257; 1 bound volume (Object 105)
  - Camera Lenses, 1937; cap1_ref258; 1 bound volume (Object 106)
  - Studies in Spectrum Analysis, 1878; cap1_ref259; 1 bound volume (Object 107)
  - A Manual of Photographic Chemistry, 1883; cap1_ref260; 1 bound volume (Object 108)
  - A First Book of Lenses, 1901; cap1_ref261; 1 bound volume (Object 109)
  - Photography Indoors and Out, 1897; cap1_ref262; 1 bound volume (Object 110)
  - Magnesium Light Photography, 1911; cap1_ref263; 1 bound volume (Object 111)
  - Photography in Colours, 1916; cap1_ref264; 1 bound volume (Object 112)
  - Wonders of Glass-Making in all Ages, 1872; cap1_ref265; 1 bound volume (Object 113)
  - The Science and Practice of Photographic Printing, 1925; cap1_ref266; 1 bound volume (Object 114)
  - Marion's Practical Guide to Photography, 1886; cap1_ref267 (Object 115)
  - Chemistry for Photographers, 1941; cap1_ref268; 1 bound volume (Object 116)
  - The Stereoscope and Stereoscopic Photography, undated; cap1_ref269; 1 bound volume (Object 117)
  - The Practice of Collotype, 1935; cap1_ref270; 1 bound volume (Object 118)
  - Pictoral Effect in Photography, 1881; cap1_ref271; 1 bound volume (Object 119)
  - The A B C Guide to Autotype, 1898; cap1_ref272; 1 bound volume (Object 120)
  - Aristotypes and How to Make Them, 1893; cap1_ref273; 1 bound volume (Object 121)
  - A Handbook of Photography in Colours, 1900; cap1_ref274; 1 bound volume (Object 122)
  - Photographic Reproduction Processes, 1891; cap1_ref275; 1 bound volume (Object 123)
  - A Dictionary of Photography, 1889; cap1_ref276; 1 bound volume (Object 124)
  - Photography, undated; cap1_ref277; 1 bound volume (Object 125)
  - Photography: Its History, Processes, Apparatus, and Materials, 1892; cap1_ref278; 1 bound volume (Object 126)
  - Photography Artistic & Scientific, 1895; cap1_ref279; 1 bound volume (Object 127)
  - The Complete Photographer, 1909; cap1_ref280; 1 bound volume (Object 128)
  - The Right Road to Photography: A Course of Instruction in the Theory and Practice of the Art, 1898; cap1_ref281; 1 bound volume (Object 129)
  - Photography: Its History, Processes, Apparatus, and Materials, 1892; cap1_ref282; 1 bound volume (Object 130)
  - A Handbook of Illustration, undated; cap1_ref283; 1 bound volume (Object 131)
  - Selection of Subject in Pictorial Photography, 1901; cap1_ref284; 1 bound volume (Object 132)
  - The Optical Lantern for Instruction and Amusement, 1890; cap1_ref285; 1 bound volume (Object 133)
  - A History of Photography, 1887; cap1_ref286; 1 bound volume (Object 134)
  - The Art of Retouching, 1888; cap1_ref287; 1 bound volume (Object 135)
  - The Art of Retouching, 1880; cap1_ref288; 1 bound volume (Object 136)
  - A Complete Treatsie on the Art of Retouching Photographic Negatives, 1901; cap1_ref289; 1 bound volume (Object 137)
  - The Chemistry of Photography, 1892; cap1_ref290; 1 bound volume (Object 138)
  - New York in MCMXXIII, 1923; cap1_ref291; 1 bound volume (Object 139)
  - Finger-Print Photography, 1907; cap1_ref292; 1 bound volume (Object 140)
  - Chemistry for Photographers, 1899; cap1_ref293; 1 bound volume (Object 141)
  - Picture Making by Photography, 1889; cap1_ref294; 1 bound volume (Object 142)
  - The Dictionary of Photography, 1937; cap1_ref295; 1 bound volume (Object 143)
  - Memoirs of Photochemist, 1960; cap1_ref296; 1 bound volume (Object 144)
  - Photographic Facts and Formulas, 1924; cap1_ref297; 1 bound volume (Object 145)
  - Photographic Amusements, 1931; cap1_ref298; 1 bound volume (Object 146)
  - Picture Making with Paper Negatives, 1943; cap1_ref299; 1 bound volume (Object 147)
  - Towles' Portrait Lightings, 1925; cap1_ref300; 1 bound volume (Object 148)
  - Photo-Engraving, Photo-Etching and Photo-Lithography In Line and Half Tone, 1888; cap1_ref301; 1 bound volume (Object 149)
  - Photogravure, 1930; cap1_ref302; 1 bound volume (Object 150)
  - Instruction in Photography, 1905; cap1_ref303; 1 bound volume (Object 151)
  - The International Annual of Anthony's Photographic Bulletin and American Process Year-Book, 1899; cap1_ref304; D. Appleton and Company; Lommel, Eugene, 1837-1899; 1 bound volume (Object 152)
  - A Handbook of Photography in Colors, 1900; cap1_ref305; 1 bound volume (Object 153)
  - Dry Plates, undated; cap1_ref306; 1 bound volume (Object 154)
  - The Gum Bichromate Book, 1978; cap1_ref307; 1 bound volume (Object 155)
  - Photographic Mosaics: An Annual Record of Photographic Process, 1890; cap1_ref308; 1 bound volume (Object 156)
  - Photography, 1851; cap1_ref309; 1 bound volume (Object 157)
  - The Principles of Photographic Pictorialism, 1930; cap1_ref310; 1 bound volume (Object 158)
  - Lantern-Slides, 1890; cap1_ref311; 1 bound volume (Object 159)
  - The Photographic Negative, 1888; cap1_ref312; 1 bound volume (Object 160)
  - The Modern Practice of Retouching Negatives, 1890; cap1_ref313; 1 bound volume (Object 161)
  - Pictoral Effect in Photography, 1897; cap1_ref314; 1 bound volume (Object 162)
  - Photographic Printing Methods, 1889; cap1_ref315; 1 bound volume (Object 163)
  - The Gelatino-Chloride of Silver Printing-Out Process, 1891; cap1_ref316; 1 bound volume (Object 164)
  - Modern Dry Plates; or Emulsion Photography, 1881; cap1_ref317; 1 bound volume (Object 165)
  - The Photographic Instructor, 1895; cap1_ref318; 1 bound volume (Object 166)
  - The American Annual of Photography and Photographic Times, 1893; cap1_ref319; 1 bound volume (Object 167)
  - Practical Photography How to Choose and Use a Lens, 1915; cap1_ref320; 1 bound volume (Object 168)
  - The Lens, 1902; cap1_ref321; 1 bound volume (Object 169)
  - The Evolution of Photography, 1890; cap1_ref322; 1 bound volume (Object 170)
  - The Practical Printer, 1874; cap1_ref323; 1 bound volume (Object 171)
  - El Rayo Solar, 1884; cap1_ref324; 1 bound volume (Object 172)
  - Optics for Photographers, 1918; cap1_ref325; 1 bound volume (Object 173)
  - Carbon Printing, undated; cap1_ref326; 1 bound volume (Object 174)
  - A Treatise on Photographic Optics, 1898; cap1_ref327; 1 bound volume (Object 175)
  - Photographic Lenses, undated; cap1_ref328; 1 bound volume (Object 176)
  - Photographic Lenses: How to Choose, and How to Use, 1895; cap1_ref329; 1 bound volume (Object 177)
  - Lens Work for Amateurs, 1919; cap1_ref330; 1 bound volume (Object 178)
  - Dark Room Work, 1912; cap1_ref331; 1 bound volume (Object 179)
  - Developers and Development, 1912; cap1_ref332; 1 bound volume (Object 180)
  - Sensitized Papers, 1894; cap1_ref333; 1 bound volume (Object 181)
  - Photo Lighting, 1902; cap1_ref334; 1 bound volume (Object 182)
  - Pictoral Landscape Photography, 1921; cap1_ref335; 1 bound volume (Object 183)
  - The Philadelphia Photographer, 1865; cap1_ref336; 1 bound volume (Object 184)
  - The Philadelphia Photographer, 1867; cap1_ref337; 1 bound volume (Object 185)
  - Homley Scenes from Great Painters, undated; cap1_ref338; 1 bound volume (Object 186)